Guide to the Andrew Jackson Faulk Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Packard, Samuel W. Letter to Faulk. February 22, 1879. 1 p.
Padelford, Seth. Letter to Governor Faulk, transmitting a copy of the resolution of the General Assembly of Rhode Island ratifying the Fifteenth Amendment to the Constitution. Certified by John R. Bartlett, Secretary of State. January 20, 1870. Printed. 2 pp.
Painter, John V. Letter to Faulk. May 26, 1870. 1 p.
Parker, O. H. Letter to Faulk. April 30, 1891. Written on the verso of a broadside, "Historical Society of South Dakota. Circular No. 1." 1891. 22 x 28 cm.
Parmer, Charlotte Faulk (Mrs. Mark M.) "Pet." Two letters to her father, A. J. Faulk. January 25, 1883, April 9, 1885. 5 pp.
---- Two letters to her mother. November 3, 1885, March 21, 1886. 8 pp.
Parmer, Mark M. Three letters to Faulk. January 30, 1868- September 14, 1879. 9 pp.
---- Letter to Mrs. Faulk. August 20, 1881. 2 pp.
Philips, W. C. Letter to Governor Faulk. December 8, 1868. Printed form. 1 p.
Pickler, John Alfred. Letter to Faulk. July 1, 1884. 1 p.
Picotte, Charles F. Letter to Faulk. April 25, 1892. 2 pp.
Picotte, Margaret. Power of attorney to W. W. Brookings. December 26, 1868. Witnessed by C. F. Picotte and A. G. Guyon. Printed form. 1 p.
Pierce, H. A. Letter to Faulk. March 9, 1870. 4 pp.
Preble, George Henry. Letter to Faulk. January 26, 1867. Signature only. 2 pp.
Raymond, John Baldwin. Two letters to Faulk. August 31, 1877, October 29, 1879. 3 pp.
Rayner, Kenneth. Two letters to Faulk. December 17, 1877, June 4, 1879. 2 pp.
Reed, William M. Letter to Faulk. October 10, 1879. 2 pp.
Reilly, Edward. Letter to Faulk. August 6, 1866. 2 pp.
Rencontre, Zephyr. Letters patent. A grant of land to Rencontre under treaty of April 19, 1858, signed by Abraham Lincoln, President, Edward D. Neill, Secretary, G. W. Granger, recorder. Recorded May 4, 1870. Certified a true copy by W. W. Warford, recorder of deeds, March 5, 1878. 3 pp.
Reynolds, M. H. (Mrs. Absalom). Letter to Faulk. September 28, 1879. 4 pp.
Robinson, J. F. Two letters to Faulk. December 6, 1866, September 21, 1869. 2 pp.
Rossteuscher, Charles F. Letter to Governor Faulk. January 4, 1868. 1 p.
Rowland, William S. Letter to Faulk. October 20, 1866. 2 pp.
Seward, Frederick William. Three letters to Faulk. October 2, 1866- February 17, 1869. Signatures only. 4 pp.
Shannon, Peter C. Four letters to Faulk. May 27 [1873]-May 22, 1894. 4 pp.
---- Appointment of Faulk as clerk of the District Court of the United States, Second Judicial District of Dakota Territory, and register in Chancery. November 29, 1873, renewed January 12, 1874. 1 p.
---- Appointment of Faulk as clerk of the District Court for Yankton County. November 29, 1873, renewed January 12, 1874. 1 p.
---- Appointment of Faulk as U.S. commissioner for the Second Judicial District. March 2, 1874. 1 p.
Sheldon, Charles H. Two letters to Faulk. February 9, 20, 1895. Typewritten. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Captain H. A. Humphrey. February 20, 1893. Copy. 3 pp.
Smith, Edward W. Letter to Faulk. August 5, 1867. Signature only. 1 p.
Smith, R. W. Two letters to Faulk. October 6, 1876, August 26, 1878. 4 pp.
Spink, Solomon Lewis. Two letters to Faulk. June 16, 1867, March 22, 1869. 3 pp.
Stevens, Thaddeus. Letter to H[?] K[?] Fowler. February 21, 1867. 1 p.
Stein, William I. Letter to Faulk. August 28, 1874. 1 p.
Strike-the-Ree (Palaneapape). Letter to Faulk. April 21, 1879. 1 p.
Stutsman, Enos. Six letters to Faulk. October 1, 1866-June 6, 1870. 16 pp.
---- Two letters to W. A. Burleigh. May 10, 1866, March 31, 1869. With reprints of Burleigh's speeches in the House of Representatives on the Indian question, July 21, 1868, and on the bill to provide a territorial government for Wyoming, July 23, 1868. 11 pp.
Sully, Alfred. Note of the delivery of one ambulance to Governor Faulk, August 1, 1867. Endorsed: "Turned over to John A. Burbank Gov. etc. May 1, 1869. A. J. Faulk, Governor." 1 p.
Swett, Leonard B. Letter to Faulk. November 18, 1875. 1 p.
Terry, Alfred Howe. Letter to General E. D. Townsend. May 29, 1867. "Official" copy by Edward Smith. 1 p.
[Thomas], Camilla. Two letters to Faulk. July 30, 1871, March 5, 1875. 9 pp.
Thomas, Robert I. Letter to Faulk. January 3, 1867. 2 pp.
Thompson, Clark W. Letter to Faulk. January 20, 1864. 1 p.
Todd, John Blair Smith. Letter to Faulk. September 9, 1866. 1 p.
Tripp, Bartlett. Letter to Faulk. January 19, 1877. 1 p.
Turner [?], S. S. Letter to Faulk. September 1, 1873. 1 p.
Tyndale, Sharon. Letter to Faulk. December 8, 1868. Signed: "per Lotus Viles." 1 p.
U.S. President (Andrew Johnson). Appointment of Faulk as governor of Dakota Territory. August 4, 1866. Signed by Andrew Johnson and William H. Seward. Engraved on vellum. 50 x 35 cm. With letter of transmittal, August 9, 1866. Form letter signed by W. H. Seward. [Before confirmation by the Senate.] 1 p.
---- Appointment of Faulk as governor "by and with the advice and consent of the Senate." March 2, 1867. Signed by Andrew Johnson and William H. Seward. Engraved on vellum. 49 1/2 x 35 cm.
Van Valzals, S. B. Letter to Faulk. March 24, 1872. 3 pp.
Van Vleck, Frederick B. Five letters to Faulk. May 30, 1866- May 27, 1871. 16 pp.
Waddell, William Coventry H. Letter to Faulk. August 3, 1871. 1 p.
Ward, Morris E. Letter to Faulk. December 22, 1867. 1 p.
Warner, Oliver. Letter to Faulk. March 29, 1867, transmitting a copy of the resolution of the Massachusetts Legislature ratifying the amendment to the Constitution of the United States passed March 20, 1867. Printed. 3 pp.
Washabaugh, Frank J. Letter to Faulk. November 23, 1879. 3 pp.
Weitzel, Mrs. Eliza B. Letter to Faulk. February 23, 1881. 3 pp.
White, Ashton J. H. Two letters to Faulk. September 7, November 19, 1868. Signature only. 3 pp.
Whitney, Oscar. Letter to Faulk. December 3, 1879. 2 pp.
---- Letter to Columbus Delano. December 11, 1873. Copy by Faulk, signed by Whitney. 8 pp.
Wicker, J. H. Eight letters to J. M. Stone. June 27, 1872- November 14, 1878. 14 pp.
Wicker, Meckling & Co. Letter to J. M. Stone. January 2, 1875. 1 p.
Wilkins, Turney M. Letter to Faulk. January 21, 1872. 4 pp.
Wilkinson, Mahlon. Two letters to Faulk. April 27, 1868, April 14, 1869. Signature only. 2 pp.
Willamov. Letter to the District Court of Dakota. Imperial Russian Legation, May 2, 1878. With copy of letter in answer addressed to J. P. Kidder, signed by Faulk, May 17, 1878. 4 pp.
Williams, John. Letter to Faulk. January 23, 1867. 1 p.
Williams, Thomas. Letter to Faulk. December 20, 1866. 2 pp.
Wilson, James S. Four letters to Faulk. General Land Office. January 28, 1867-August 10, 1868. 8 pp.
Woodward, Joseph T. Letter to Governor Faulk, transmitting a copy of "Acts and Resolves of Maine for 1868." December 23, 1868. Printed. 1 p.
"Plan of grounds of Major J. M. Stone, Yankton. Cleveland & French, March 1874, Landscape Architects, Chicago." 43 1/2 x 63 cm.
Pencil sketch in color, inscribed: "This view of an Indian camp was made by a son of Congressman Burleigh." [n.d.] 32 1/2 x 16 1/2 cm.
Pencil sketch of Governor Faulk's mother, Mrs. Margaret Faulk, drawn on the back of an unsigned draft of a letter to W. M. Watson. July 9, 1832. 19 x 18 cm.
Indians of North America -- Government relations; Dakota Territory -- Politics and government; Public officers -- Dakota Territory; Brodhead, John H.; Burleigh, Andrew F.; Burleigh, Walter A. (Walter Atwood), 1820-1896; Chandler, William E(William Eaton), 1835-1917; Faulk, Andrew Jackson, 1814-1898; Faulk, Thomas B.; Humphrey, H. A.; Ordway, George L.; Shannon, P. C. (Peter C.), -1899; Stutsman, Enos; Wicker, J. H.; Van Vleck, Frederick B.; Dakota Territory. Governor (1866-1869: Faulk); United States. District Court (South Dakota); Britton & Gray
- Correspondence, 1835-96, n.d.; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, contains both personal and official letters. The series consists primarily of letters either to or from Andrew Jackson Faulk, although correspondence between others, such as members of Faulk's family, is also included. Additional official correspondence can be found in Series III. Official Papers.
  - Correspondence, 1835-65 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1867 Jan-Mar (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1867 Apr-Aug (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1867 Sep-Dec (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1868 Jan-Jun (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1868 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1869 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1869 Mar-Dec (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1874-75 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1876-77 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1878-79 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1880-82 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1883-84 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1885-87 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1888-96 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Personal Papers, 1817-83, n.d.; Series II
  Series II, Personal Papers, consists primarily of financial and property records, in addition to personal notes and memoranda. A number of photographs are also included in the series.
  - Photos: family, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Photos: Indians (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Photos: Indians (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Photos: military identifications, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Photos: miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Commissions, 1817-83 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Personal account books, 1861-69 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Deeds, indentures, leases (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Personal accounts, bills, etc. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Memoranda and notes (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Official Papers, 1866-1910; Series III
  Series III, Official Papers, consists of records, accounts, receipts, correspondence and official documents related to Faulk's work as Governor of Dakota Territory, Superintendent of Indian Affairs, and as Clerk of the U.S. District Court, Second Judicial District.
  - Annual reports, 1866-67 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Governor of Dakota Territory: Official papers, 1867-68 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Governor of Dakota Territory: Official papers, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Governor of Dakota Territory: accounts, 1868-69 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (I), 1866 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (II), 1866 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (I), 1867 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (II), 1867 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (I), 1868 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (II), 1868 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (I), 1869 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (II), 1869 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (III), 1869 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (IV), 1869 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (V), 1869 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts (VI), 1869 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Superintendent of Indian Affairs: accounts, 1871-75 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Letters protesting treatment and portrayal of Indians, ca. 1900-10 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Sketches: Indian village, Margaret Faulk; Plan of a garden (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper articles (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Clerk of District Court: documents, 1874-82 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Clerk of District Court: emolument returns, 1875-81 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Clerk of District Court: judicial receipts, 1873-81 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Docket of Clerk of District Court, 1875-78 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Docket of Clerk of District Court, 1878-81 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Envelopes, 1835-96; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series IV, Envelopes, consists of retained envelopes from the correspondence contained in Series I.
  - Miscellaneous addressed envelopes (Box 5, Folder 58)